Register of the Henry D. (Henry Dudley) Lytton Papers, 1938-1988
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry D. (Henry Dudley) Lytton Papers,
1938-1988.
86014
Lytton, Henry D. (Henry Dudley), 1909-
5 manuscript boxes (2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports and other writings, correspondence, memoranda, statistics, and printed matter, relating to economic aspects of geopolitics, especially during World War II and the Korean War; the efficacy of bombing policy during World War II; measurement of productivity in both industry and the public sector; Peruvian industrial productivity; demand for nickel in the United States; and development of Lebanese exports.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Board of Economic Warfare.; United States. Army Air Forces.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.; Strategic materials.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; Civil service--Labor productivity.; Labor productivity--Peru.; Nickel industry--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; Peru.; Economists.; Labor productivity.; Lebanon--Commerce.; Lebanon.; Korean War, 1950-1953.
Biographical Note
1909, Nov. 10 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1936-1938 Assistant to the President, International Statistics Bureau
1938-1939 Director, Research and Statistics, General Tung Oil Corporation
1939-1941 Assistant Editor, Ogden Publishing Company
1941-1942 Assistant Industrial Economist, Textiles and Fibers, War Production Board
1942 Commodity Specialist, Board of Economic Warfare
1942-1945 Intelligence Specialist, U.S. Army Air Forces
1945- Economic and Management Consultant
1950-1951 Industrial Economist, New York Quartermaster Procurement Agency
1951-1953 Industrial Specialist, Office of Defense Mobilization
1954 Research Assistant, Hoover Commission
1954 Executive Director, Benefits Field Supervision, Veterans Administration
1964-1965 Industrial Productivity Measurement Consultant, U.S. Aid Mission to Peru
1968 Consultant, Manufacturing Division, U.N. Conference on Trade and Development, Lebanon
1971 Visiting Lecturer, Advanced World Training Center, International Labour Office, Turin, Italy
Series Description
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1988. (Box Nos. 1-5)
  Drafts and printed copies of books, articles, clippings, correspondence, charts, reports, book reviews, reference material and photographs. Arranged chronologically.
Container List
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1988.
  SEE: Appendix for folder lists
  - General
    - General. Autobiographies, partial index and descriptive summary of the reports by Henry Lytton which comprise this collection, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Government and military supply requirements. Clipping, memoranda, reports, bulletin, and charts primarily relating to the second Hoover Commission, surplus government property, World War II and Korean War mobilization and availability of supplies, 1941-1955 (Folder 2)
  - "Corporate Program of General Tung Oil Corporation, with a Background of the Industry," 1938. Typescript copies of reports, letter and printed material relating to tung oil and castor oil, 1937-1938 (Folder 3)
  - "World Economic Factors Important for War Strategy in 1942," 1942. Summary, typescript report, correspondence, memoranda, and clippings, 1941-1984 (Folder 4)
  - "Raw Material Potential of World Areas Important for 1950 Strategy," 1950. Summary, typescript reports, correspondence, and clippings, 1947-1986 (Folder 5)
  - "Postwar Productivity of Veterans' Administration DVB Programs in the Field," 1956. Typescript and correspondence, 1956-1984 (Folder 6)
  - "A Basis for Forecasting Nickel Demand in the United States," Engineering and Mining Journal, 1957 Aug. Summary, serial issues, drafts and printed copy of article, 1956-1984 (Folder 7-8)
  - "Government Operations Can Make Sense--And Save Dollars," 1957. Summary, typescript reports, memoranda, and correspondence, 1957-1984 (Folder 9)
  - "Estimating Recent Federal Government Productivity Trends," Review of Economics and Statistics, 1959 Nov. Typescript and printed copies, correspondence, reviews, summary, notes, and printed material, 1959-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - "Estimating Recent Federal Government Productivity Trends," Review of Economics and Statistics, 1959 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Public Sector Productivity in the Truman-Eisenhower Years," Review of Economics and Statistics, 1961 May. Printed copy and printed material (Folder 2)
  - "Using Trends and Comparisons to Stimulate Government Productivity," International Review of Administrative Sciences, 1962. Printed copy, charts, notes, correspondence, and printed material, 1961-1984 (Folder 3-4)
  - "Recent Productivity Trends in Peruvian Manufacturing Industries," 1964. Printed copies, reference materials notes, and correspondence, 1964-1984 (Folder 5-6)
  - Report on Peru, 1965. Mimeographed and microfilm copies, printed material, reports, reference material, notes, correspondence, and memoranda, 1964-1967 (Folder 7)
  - Report on Peru, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - "Veterans' Administration in American Samoa," 1966. Mimeographed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Prospects for Exports from Lebanon," 1968. Typescript copies, printed material, notes, and correspondence, 1967-1983 (Folder 4-7)
  - "The Measurement of Productivity Levels and Trends in Manufacturing Industries and Industry Member Firms, 1971. Typescripts, charts and correspondence, 1967-1971 (Folder 8)
  - "The Measurement of Productivity Levels and Trends in Manufacturing Industries and Industry Member Firms, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Review of W.W. Rostow, Pre-Invasion Strategy, 1982. Drafts and printed copy, notes, and a copy of the book, 1982 (Folder 2)
  - "Bombing Policy in the Rome and Pre-Normandy Campaigns," Military Affairs, 1983 April. Report, drafts, notes, memoranda, printed material, correspondence, charts, audiovisual material, and reference material, 1944-1986 (Folder 3-7)